深海异兽
（未开发钻凿地带）
（全世界最深钻井施工中）
（天恩工业将在极深处钻探资源）
（马里亚纳海沟，深达1万1000公尺）
（往下钻凿1万1260公尺）
（每平方寸高达八吨的巨大压力）
（一片漆黑）
（无数危机，高度风险）
（深海之谜）
（该公司否认钻探地点发生怪事）
（开普勒822，8374号钻探点）
（罗巴克站641）
（出现钻井异常）
（如太空般致命）
（没有氧气与阳光）
（在高压深海工作的副作用仍不清楚）
（原因不明的异常）
（神秘失踪）
（长期孤立，难以解释的现象）
（深海爆炸）
（新发现的深海物种）
（无法解释的震动）
（异常的数值）
（天恩工业欲盖弥彰）
（天恩工业）
（开普勒工作站）
（用途：）
（罗巴克油井的指挥控制中心）
（人员：316人）
连续数月待在海底，你会日夜不分
When you're underwaterfor months at a time, you lose all senseof day and night.
只有清醒和作梦之分
And there's only awakeand dreaming.
两者其实也难以区分
Not that those thingsare easy to tell apart.
我想到…
I think,
或梦到他对我说的第一件事
he ever said to me.
他说他不相信时间
Told me he didn'tbelieve in time...
只相信瞬间
only moments.
他是个乐天派
He was aglass-half-full type.
好吧
All right.
我则是悲观主义者
I prefer it empty.
你在这里做什么？
What are you doing here?
愤世嫉俗也有好处
I mean, there's acomfort to cynicism.
能失去的比较少
There's a lotless to lose.
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
起来！
Wake up!
压力外泄
Pressure breach!
压力外泄！快到隔舱壁去
Pressure breach!We gotta get to the bulkhead!
结构完整性受损
Structuralintegrity compromised.
大家起来…快点
Everyone up! Everyone up!Come on!
结构完整性受损
Structural integritycompromised.
到底怎么回事？
What the hell is happening?
快走！压力外泄
Let's go! Pressure breach!
把隔舱壁封起来
We gotta seal the bulkhead!
减压警告，封闭隔舱壁
De-pressurizationwarning.
我没带门禁卡
- De-pressurization warning. - I don't have my keycard!
这里…
Here, here, here.
不！ 隔舱壁卡住
- No! - Bulkhead jammed.
我得马上拆开它
I gotta get insidethis thing now!
必须重开 在哪里…？
- Reboot required. - Where is it? Where is it?
天啊
Oh, my God!
快啊
Come on!
减压警告，封闭隔舱壁
De-pressurization warning.Seal the bulkhead.
快点…
Come on, come on,come on, come on.
整个油井要自爆了
The whole rigis about to implode!
不把门关上，全站都会完蛋
If you don't shut these doors, it'll take the whole stationwith us!
好啦，好了…
Okay! Okay, okay, okay,got it, got it, got it!
系统上线 -关门！
- System online. - Shut the door!
等等 -嘿…
- Wait! - Hey, hey, hey.
等我们！
Wait for us!
嘿！ -快跑！
- Hey! - Run!
快跑 -快点
- Run! - Come on!
快跑！
Guys, run! Come on, come on!
快跑过来
- Hey! Hey, hey! - Come on, guys, let's go!
快跑！
Come on, run!
诺拉，他们来不及 -等等
Norah, Norah!They're not gonna make it.
关门 -诺拉
- Close the door! - Norah!
我们得关门，否则油井会完蛋
We have to close the door,otherwise the whole rig will die.
马上关门
Shut the door now!
站体结构因突发事件而损坏
Structural failure is imminent incident.
开普勒站人员注意，站体结构即将损坏
To all Kepler Station crew,structural failure is imminent.
重复，站体结构即将损坏
Repeat, structuralfailure is imminent.
嘿…你还好吗？
Hey, hey. You okay?
那是地震吗？
Was that an earthquake?
不知道
I don't know.
规模应该有10或11
Had to have been likea ten or eleven.
我根本不知道要转到哪个频道…
I don't even knowwhat channel we'd be...
全体人员前往逃生舱准备撤离
All personnelreport to pod bays for immediate evacuation.
这是开普勒，控制中心听到了吗？
This is Kepler.Control, can you hear me?
开普勒站状态，70%受损
Kepler Stationstatus, 70% compromised.
反应器不稳
Reactor unstable.
控制中心，这是开普勒，听到了吗？
Control, this is Kepler,can you hear me?
开普勒站状态，70%受损
Kepler Stationstatus, 70% compromised.
求救…
Mayday. Mayday. Mayday.
有人听到吗？
Can anyone hear me?
我们得到逃生舱区去
We have to get to the pod bays.
走吧
Come on.
身为工作人员
As a crewmember, we want you to know
我们不只是团队
that you're notjust part of a team,
更是一个大家庭
you're part ofour family.
不对，那边过不去
No, no, no.That doesn't go through.
有意见请向您的长官申诉
Havea complaint? Address itto your superior officer.
成功了，现在只要找到最近的逃生舱就好
Oh, yes, working. I just got to findthe nearest pods.
资深工程师请至工程部门报到
Senior engineers,please report to engineering.
你叫罗德里哥吧？
Rodrigo, right?
对
Yeah.
我是诺拉
Norah.
我知道，我通常值日班
I-I know. I usually workwith the day shift.
你能帮我吗？ -没问题
- Can you...? Can you help me out here? - Sure, I can.
你是电脑工程师吗？
Um, are you a computer engineeror something?
机械工程师 -好
- Mechanical. - Okay.
我能重开断路器
I can reset breakers.
我在这里待了一段时间
I've been down here for a bit.
你得知道…
Hey, you gotta know...
那不是我们的错
that wasn't our fault.
你拯救了整个油井
I mean,you-you saved the entire rig.
我根本不知道要关门
Hmm.
隔舱壁关闭
Bulkheads closed.
你真的认为那是地震吗？
Do you... Do you really thinkthat was an earthquake?
不
No.
我不知道
I-I don't know.
不妙，海底电缆断了
That's not good. The hardline's been severed.
天线也没了，我们联络不到海面
Antenna's gone. I don't eventhink we can reach the surface.
尽快前往最近的逃生舱
...to the nearestescape pod as soon as possible.
CR7区有逃生舱
There's-there'sevac pods in CR-7.
我们能搞定的
Hey, we got this, all right?
有些水绝对是污水
Some of this wateris definitely sewage.
欢迎登上开普勒站
Welcomeaboard the Kepler Station, located just a mile awayfrom the Roebuck...
距离罗巴克站1600公尺
泰坦级姊妹站…
The titan-classsister station...
开普勒…抽取原油…
The Kepler...pumps a crude...
很荣幸接待您，祝您愉快
...and we hopeyou enjoy your stay.
能够钻过那边吗？
Can we...Can we dig through there?
我进去看看
I'll look inside.
我能进来这里
Yeah, I can fit up here,if you can.
过来看看
Come check.
哈罗？有人听到吗？
Hello? Can anyone hear me?
哈罗…
Hello? Hello?
你听到了吗？
Hey, do you hear that?
嘿 -哈罗
- Hey! - Hello!
继续说话，我听到了
Hey, keep talking, man.I can hear you.
我在石块底下
I'm under the rock!
把它拿过去
Take him, take him.
保罗？这里…嗨
Paul? Here, here, here, here.Hey, you.
下面怎么了？你的腿还好吗？
What's-what's going ondown there? Your legs all right?
嗯 -好
- Yeah. - Okay.
你需要什么？ -离开这里
What do you need? To get the heck out of here.
我知道，我能怎么做？
Yeah, yeah, I know.What can I do?
好
- All right, all right. - All right.
还好吗？ -嗯
- You good? - Yeah.
这里 -嘿
- All right. Here. - Hey.
诺拉？ -你没事，嗨
- Norah? - You're good. Hi!
对
Yes.
你这贴心的平胸小妖精
You sweet,flat-chested elven creature.
深呼吸，你没事
Okay, just breathe for a second.You're all good.
小保罗还好吗？
- Is Lil Paul okay? - Yeah, he's cool.
它没事。要站起来看看吗？
- Let me help you. - You wanna try to stand up?
-好
- Yeah.
大哥，上来
- All right, buddy. Here we go.
抓住他手臂
Grab his arm?
不要…等等
No, no, no. Wait. No, no.
你卡到什么东西吗？
Okay, are you caughtin anything?
没有，用力一点
No, no, no,let's just be stronger.
好了
Okay.
小保罗给我
Okay, give me Lil Paul.
来 -谢谢
- Yeah, here. - Thank you.
我们该走了
Gotta go.
我有睡袍和幸运袜
Okay, I got my robeand my lucky sock.
我们要干嘛？
What are we doing?
我们去CR7区的逃生舱
The evac pods in CR-7.
好
- We're headed there, okay? - Okay.
上层快塌了，我们快走
The upper decks are collapsing.We gotta move fast.
钻过那里？
Through that thing?
你们疯了
You guys are crazy.
我很大只耶
I'm a big boy.
我想…
All right. I think...
等一下
Hold up.
隔舱壁关闭
Bulkheads closed.
进水已控制
Flooding contained.
没事
Okay.
你们还好吗？ -还好
- You guys okay? - Yeah.
什么？
这里有人
There's-there's someone up here.
是麦凯伦
It's... It's McClellen.
天啊
Jesus.
小罗
Hey, Rod.
走吧
Come on, bud.
我看到逃生舱区了
Guys, I see the pod bay.
注意…全体开普勒人员…
Attention! Attention! All Kepler crew...
队长？
Cap?
哇靠！他没跑？
Holy shit.He stayed behind?
等等，他怎么坐在那里？
Wait, why's hejust sitting there?
惨了
Oh, shit.
什么惨了？
"Shit?" What's...What's "oh shit"? What?
逃生舱没了
The evac pods are gone.
把线路打开 -队长
- I need the line open. - Captain!
嗨！
Hey!
诺拉，你还活着
Norah. You're alive.
队长
Cap.
门卡住了
The door's jammed.
罗德里哥，保罗
Rodrigo, Paul.
你们去察看潜水器的状况，快
I need you two to check wherewe are on submersible. Now.
好
All right, all right.
从一到十级，油井状况多严重？
On a scale from one to ten,how bad's my rig?
十级
Uh, ten.
七成受损
You're 70% compromised.
如果呼吸太用力，我们…
Honestly, you-you breathetoo hard in here, we're...
等等，我看看
Wait. Let me see.
我不懂，那是地震还是…
I don't get it. Was thatlike an earthquake or...
不知道，我也想搞清楚
I don't know.I'm trying to figure it out.
你怎么还在这里？
Why are you still here?
你应该上去了，这里本来有逃生舱
You should have gone up.There were pods here.
因为这是队长的责任
'Cause that's what captains do.
谁在乎？你有小孩，应该上去的
Who cares? You have a kid,you should have gone up.
能请你坐下吗？
Can you, uh, can yousit down, please?
我们谁都会立即把你推上逃生舱
Any one of us would haveshoved your ass onto that pod immediately.
听我说
Listen to me.
每个人都要活着离开，懂吗？
Everybody's getting outof here alive, you hear me?
好吗？
Okay?
贴在耳朵上
Hold that on your ear.
我已经送了22个人上去
I already sent 22 up.
史密斯说有七人死亡
Smith reported seven dead.
我发现三个
I found three.
李、崔维斯和麦凯伦
It was, it was Lee,Travis and McClellen,
麦凯伦的手还有温度。所以我知道是他
so I-I know it was McClellen.
她距离我三层楼，两小时前我还在刷牙
I mean, she livesthree floors up, and I was brushing my teeth,like, two hours ago.
我不得不关闭整个东翼的门
- I-I had to shut the door on the entire East wing.
不要这样
Don't do this to yourself.
所以可能还有人
So, actually, you know what,there could be more.
不要想过去，往前看
Stop thinking back,look forward.
往前看，看着我
Look forward. Look at me.
盯着光，快
Now you follow the light.Come on.
眼睛跟着光移动
Follow the light.Ca va ca va.
队长，潜水器不能用
Cap,that isa no-go on the submersibles.
收到，我派诺拉到控制室
Copy that. I'm sending Norahto the control room.
爱蜜莉，你还好吗？
Emily, are you okay? Hey.
天啊，你还活着 -诺拉？
- Oh, my gosh. You're alive. - Norah?
嗨 -你还活着
- Hey. - You're alive.
大哥 -我讨厌抱抱
- Dude. - Ah, I hate that.
有听到什么吗？ -没有
- Have you heard anything? - No, no. Nothing.
冷却塔怎么样？
- How are the cooling towers? - I haven't checked 'em yet.
我还没看，你要看吗？ -好
看那边有没有活口
See if anybody'salive out there.
隔舱壁关闭
Bulkheads closed...
给你
Hey, hey.
有人会来救我们吧？
Someone's coming. Right?
他们会派人来 -不知道，谢谢
They're gonna...They're gonna send someone. I don't know. Thank you.
我确定他们已经派人来了
I'm pretty surethey already sent someone.
不晓得我们有没有时间等他们
I'm less sure we have the timeto wait for them.
诺拉 -是
- Norah. - Yeah.
冷却塔，状况如何？
So, the cooling towers?What are we getting?
不太妙
Nothing good.
上层都塌了，冷却塔也没了
All the upper deckshave collapsed and we lost the cooling towers.
开普勒的核心十分不稳
The core of the Kepleris completely unstable.
什么叫不稳？我们都会死吗？
Wait, what do youmean "unstable"? Like, poof,we all die "unstable"?
什么意思，诺拉？ -热核心
What are wetalking about here, Norah?
有大量能量无处可去
That's a lot of energywith nowhere to go.
这个实习生吓到我了
Okay, the intern'sfreaking me out.
谁能解释到底怎么回事？
Can somebody just explainwhat the hell's going on here?
我是研究助理
Research assistant.
如果核心熔毁，会产生高热
If there's a meltdown,there's gonna be a lot of heat.
造成闪沸、爆炸，很难说
There's gonna bea flash boil, explosions.
我常看日本动画，只知道这样
I don't really know. I watch alot of anime. That's all I know.
我也喜欢日本动画
Oh, you watch anime?I like anime.
他说得对，30分钟后熔毁
No, I mean, he's right. We have about 30 minutestill meltdown.
我们会被炸成肉酱，飞到海面
And, uh, it's gonna blow usinto tiny pieces to the surface.
别人会发现我们漂浮在海上
And people are gonna find us,like, floating around.
隔舱壁受损
Bulkhead compromised.
大家听好
Okay, guys, listen.
逃生舱没了，潜艇也故障
The escape pods are goneand the sub is out of order.
我们再也收不到无线电讯号
And we're not gettingany more radio signals.
开普勒的结构摇摇欲坠
And the structure of the Kepleris totally unsound.
队长，你最好有哏，前面讲得…
Captain, there better bea good punchline, 'cause this setup is...
不好笑 -不好笑
- So weak. - ...weak.
我们到罗巴克站去
We go for the Roebuck.
罗巴克站？
The Roebuck?
它距离我们有1.6公里远
It's a mile downand a mile that way.
你在说什么？ -对啊
- What are you talking about? - Yeah.
而且怎么过去？
How would we even get there?
用走的
We walk.
什么？
We what?
用走的
Walk.
走过去？
We walk?
你们把我挖出来就为了这个？
That's what you dug meout of the rubble for?
我不能用走的
I can't walk.
我连深潜装都没有
I don't even have a suit.
听好，听我说
Listen, listen. Listen to me.
我们这么办
Here's what we're gonna do.
我们下到载货电梯去，降至海床
We're gonna drop down to thecargo elevator to the seafloor.
然后走通道到中点站
Then we use the access tunnelto get to the Midpoint station.
在那里填充并清洁循环呼吸器
There we can chargeand clean the rebreathers.
再循着海床上的标记到罗巴克站
And then we follow the markers
在一片漆黑中漫无目的地走？
So we just go in the pitch black and we walk without knowingwhere we're going
而且氧气不足，这就是计划？
with insufficient oxygen?
没错
- That's the plan? - That's the plan.
大家同意吗？诺拉，你同意吗？
Everybody down with that?Norah, you okay with that?
你知道深潜装不能撑那么久
The suits can't be down therethat long. You know that.
不是每个人都有丰富潜水经验
Not everyone hereis an experienced diver and...
谁都说不准
Than we never know.
我不是想要…
I'm-I'm not trying to be...
你能承认那样可能没命吗？
Can you just admitwe might die doing that?
可能
Yeah. But can you admitthat we might live doing this?
你能承认也可能因此获救吗？
旧的薛波站呢？不是比较近？
Hey, what aboutthe old Shepard Station? Isn't that closer?
薛波站没了，那里空无一物
Shepard Station's gone.There's nothing there.
大伙，你们得听听这个
Uh, you guys,you need to hear this.
这是好事吗？
Can this besomething good?
可以来件好事吗？可以吗？
Could we please haveone good thing? Could we?
我想这是钻凿点传来的最后讯号
I think this was the lasttransmission from the drill site.
求救…
Mayday, mayday!
我们受损了，因十级…
We've been compromised by category ten...
那是什么鬼声音？
Now, what the hellwas that noise?
而且外面温度骤升十度
Also, the temperature outsidejumped ten degrees.
那我们走路时会很温暖
Great, so it'll be warm whenwe're walking across the plateau.
海水不会那样，不可能
The water doesn't do that.That's impossible.
那是上次地震后的余震
That's just aftershocksfrom the last earthquake, okay?
因为我们钻得太深了
It's 'causewe drilled too deep. Okay?
这是我常在讲的板块结构
It's those tectonic platesI talk about all the time.
太扯了，太扯了
This is insane.Okay, this is insane.
我们去罗巴克站
We go for the Roebuck.
怎样？要做就做整套
What? If we're gonnado this, let's do it!
对不对？
Am I right?
我让步，关小声点
All right, we can compromise.I can turn it down.
爱蜜莉，裤子脱掉，不然穿不下
Lose your pants.They won't fit in the suit.
A层受损
Deck A compromised.
隔舱壁关闭
Bulkheads closed.
进水已控制
Flooding contained.
以前有人在外面走过吗？
Has anyone everwalked out there before?
不只是修管线
Longer than to fix a pipe.I mean, just...
真的出去走？
Just walked?
没有
No.
看头盔够不够，找出六个能用的
Check if we have enough helmets. I just need you to findsix good ones.
诺拉
Hey, Norah.
嘿
Hey.
谢谢 -不客气
- Thank you. - Yeah, sure.
你还好吗？
Hey. How you doing?
准备好了吗？
You ready?
好
All right.
内裤也破了？拜托
These are ripped too? Come on!
一定会很惨
All right, this is gonna suck.
好了
Okay.
抱歉…
Oh, sorry, sorry!
行吗？
Okay. Good?
去着装
Go suit up.
氧气充足
Your air is good.
谢谢
Thank you.
把这些东西清掉
Okay, clearall this shit from the deck.
你在想什么？
What are you thinking?
我对于刚刚听到的怪声有不好预感
I'm thinkingI really didn't like
我们应该拿点家伙
We should take something.
对
Yeah.
有道理
That's a very valid point.
我看看你的背
Okay. Let me see your back.
好，最后检查
Okay. Last checks.
出发
Let's go.
大家听好
All right, listen up.
注意下降速率，遵守所有安全守则
We watch our descent rateand follow all safety protocols.
记住，这些深潜装很危险
Remember,these suits are dangerous.
笑什么？
Hey, what's so funny?
我没办法，我不行 -你可以
- I can't do this. I can't. - Yes, you can.
你可以…
Yes, you can. Yes, you can.Yes, you can.
没事，只是搭电梯
It's all right. It's all right.It's just an elevator, all right?
到过磅站都有灯光，我们跟着管线走就对了
It's all lit upto the weigh station. You just follow the pipeline.
你做得到，来吧
You can do it. Come on, come on.
云霄飞车最恐怖的是什么？
Hey, what's the scariestpart of a roller coaster?
排队的时候
Waiting in line.
对吧？
Ready?
我会一步一步陪着你
I'm gonna be right therewith you. Every step.
主桥受损
Main bridge compromised.
我们该走了
We have to move.
好，大家下水吧
All right.Everybody in the pool.
该出发了
Okay, we gotta go.
刚才是上面一层
That was one level above us.
这是下一层，走吧
This one's next. Let's go.
结构完整性受损
Structural integritycompromised.
带我们下去
Take us down.
“若不知道怎么走，任何路都能带你到达”
"If you don't knowwhere you're going, any road can getyou there."
大哥
Dude.
怎样？不是我说的，书上写的
What? It's not me, Norah.It's from a book.
走吧
Let's go.
我们都知道你不识字
We all know youcan't read.
我不想吓人，一旦到了下面
All right,I don't wanna scare anyone, but once we getto the depth
我们就得跳到货物升降机上
we're gonna have tojump to the cargo lift.
好，出发
Okay, here we go.Shit.
可恶，外舱口毁了
Exterior hatch,it's ripped to shreds.
大家准备，抓紧
Everybody, get ready.
压力会重击我们，改用手控
Override it.
它一打开我们就没事了
As long as it opens,we'll be fine.
队长，这东西有问题
Captain, I don't knowwhat's going on with this thing.
继续试
Well,keep trying.
罗德里哥 -怎么回事？
Rodrigo.
让门关着…
Keep the door closed.Keep the door closed!
惨了！待在原地，闭上眼睛
Stay where you are.Close your eyes.
没事，爱蜜莉，你没事
It's okay, Em.You're good, you're good.
听好，你没事，闭上眼睛
Listen. Listen.
走吧，爱蜜莉，踩在边缘上
Let's go, Emily.Step to the edge.
你该跳了
You have to jump now.
诺拉，他死了
Norah, he's gone.
换你，你该跳了
It's your turn.You need to jump.
他明知那顶头盔有瑕疵
He knew thatthat helmet was faulty.
我知道他晓得
I mean, I-I-I knowthat he knew it.
听好
Listen.
我明白你的感受，我知道不公平
I know how you feel.I know it's unfair.
你得化悲愤为力量
But you're gonna have totake it and use it.
好
Yeah. Okay.
走吧
Come on.
我们越快离开工作站越好
The sooner we get clear of the station the better.
我没亲眼见过任何人死掉
I've never seenanyone die before.
我看过一个人死掉
I saw somebody die.
没见过任何人自爆
I've never seen anybody implode.
你笑什么？
What are you laughing at?
我想到罗德里哥有时会做一件事
Uh, I was justthinking of this thing that Rodrigo did sometimes.
他总是说有新的笑话，然后又讲老哏
He'd always sayhe had a new joke, and then he'd tellthe same stupid joke.
我在笑那个笑话
I was... laughing at that joke.
什么笑话？
Yeah, what was it?
鲨鱼吞了绿豆会变什么？
What did the fish say whenit bumped into the brick wall?
绿豆沙（鲨）
"Dam."
好冷的笑话
Pretty stupid joke.
不管是什么，可能在我们下面
It looks likewhatever it is might be on the deck below us.
应该是其中一个逃生舱传的求救讯号
I think it's a distress signalfrom one of the pods.
多远？
How far?
200多公尺
Two hundred more meters.
为什么它不传往海面去？
Why wouldn't it begoing to the surface?
可能只剩一半电力
Maybe it's only gothalf a charge.
它停在我们底下的平台上
It's definitely stoppedon the platform below us.
生还者
Survivor.
可能是个生还者
It could be a survivor.
各位，必须有人着装
Guys, somebody's gonnahave to suit up.
爱蜜莉，你表现的时候到了
All right, Emily,this is your time.
什么？
What?
闹你的
I'm just messing with you.
来，拿去
Here, take him.
拿着这只兔子
Take this bunny.
我把它交给你
I bequeath it to you.
它有三长两短，我不会放过你
If he doesn't make it,I'll haunt you.
我们走吧
Let's go, guys.
我们不知道开普勒多久会爆炸
We don't know how longuntil the Kepler blows.
我们去找死吧
Let's go putour lives in danger.
小心 -我们马上回来
- Be careful. - We'll be right back.
保罗疯了，对吧？
Paul's crazy. Right?
我想是吧
Yeah. I guess so.
队长，要怎么办？
Hey,Captain, what do we do?
如果找到尸体的话
With the body, when we find it.
我们说的是可能的生还者
We're talking abouta possible survivor, Paul.
好吧
Okay.
那假设一下
Then hypothetically.
我们刚好碰到一具死尸
Let's say we were to comeacross a body and it was dead.
拿件遗物带给他家人
Just grab somethingwe can take back to his family.
好，我知道怎么做了
It's okay. Iknow what to do.
噢!大英雄出现了
Oh, really?We got G.I. Joe over here.
我们即将触底
And we are about to touch...
倒数三，二，一
in three, two, one.
定位
We're locked in.
好，准备好了吗？好了
All right. - Ready? - Yeah.
帅
Yeah. Yeah!
趁开普勒垮掉前搞定吧
Let's get this donebefore the Kepler comes down on our asses.
好
Okay.
打开所有监视器画面
Turn on all the camera feedswe have available.
人在逃生舱里能活多久？
How long cansomeone survive in a pod?
如果失去动力，不久
If he lost power, not long.
尤其在这个深度
Especially at this depth.
两位，现在开始帮你们减压
Okay, guys, we're startingthe decompression now.
你们结婚了吗？
Are either of you two married?
曾经结过
Was.
小孩呢？
Kids?
女儿
Daughter.
她多大了？
How-how old is she?
14岁
Fourteen.
这年纪的女生爱闹别扭
That's a tough age for a girl.
一个阶段，过去就好了
I mean, it's-it's a phase.It will pass.
她不是14岁
She's not 14.
艾丽跟我差不多大吧？
Allie? She's gotta belike my age, right?
我说14岁吗？
Who said 14? Did I say that?
对
Yeah.
我不知道为何那么说
Well, I don't knowwhy I said it.
你神智不清了，阿北
You're losing it, old man.
在海底快痴呆了
You're going senile down here.
这是正常的神经反应
It's actually a normalneurological reaction.
面对死亡时，时间… -听我说
When you're facing death,time just... Listen to me. Listen to me.
你不会死，好吗？
You're not gonna die. Okay?
好
All right.
史上最烂的点子
Worst idea ever.
反正就出发吧
Let's do it anyway.
戴上头盔，准备出发
Helmets on.Locked and loaded.
你们有养狗吗？
Either of you have dogs?
进水，诺拉
Flood it, Norah!
进水
Flooding.
我有一只柯基犬
I have a corgi.
没训练过，现在有点麻烦
Not house-trained, so he'skind of a nightmare right now,
没想到我会这么想它
but I didn't thinkI would miss him this much.
舱口封闭，我们出来了
Okay, hatch is sealed.We're outside.
进入待命状态
Okay, I'll put us on standby.
请打开泛光灯
Turn the floodlights on, please.
队长，平台不太稳
Cap, this platform'snot too stable.
不知道应该在这里待多久
I, uh, don't know how longwe should be out here.
天啊
Oh, God.
两位，继续往前走
Guys, keep on walking forward.
走20公尺
Like 20 meters.
看看右边有什么
Check what'son the right.
什么都看不到，我的还是他的右边？
I can't see shit.My right or his right?
那是什么鬼？
What thehell is that?
是我崩溃了，还是有鸟在吱吱叫？
Am I cracking upor is there, like, like, a birdchirping right now?
这里什么都没听到
We're not hearinganything up here.
队长，说话吧
All right,Captain, talk to us.
快到了吗？这里什么都看不见
We close? We can't seeanything out here.
其实你应该在它正前方
Honestly, you should beright in front of it.
好
Okay.
没看到
I can't see shit.
等等
Oh, hold up.
看到了吗？
You see that?
哇靠
Holy shit.
这东西怎么了？
What the hellhappened to this thing?
看来它自爆了，有东西
Looks like it imploded.There's, uh, something.
上面整个都是
Something all over it.
看到没？
You seeing this?
那是什么？
What is that?
我得靠近看，可能是海藻
I would need to takea closer look. It could besome sort of an-an algae.
看过这种东西吗？
You ever seeanything like that?
看起来…
This looks...
不像海藻
It doesn't looklike algae.
里面有人吗？
Is there anybody in it?
空的
Empty.
找到一样东西
I got something.
皮夹
Wallet.
太好了，可以刷他的卡
Great. We can usehis credit cards.
队长，这里没人
All right, Captain,there's no body,
拜托让我们离开，以免…
so can we pleaseand thank you get the hell out of herebefore we...
算了，这里有具尸体被电线…
Scratch that. There's a body.It's entangled...
应该叫他们回来
They should just come back.
缠住
...in the coils.
别看了，回来吧
Dude, don't check it out.Just come back.
快回来 -等等
- Just come back. - Wait.
有看到他的背吗？
Do you see his back?
你们看到了吗？ -让他们回来吧
- Can you guys see that? - Let's just bring them back.
你们回来吧
Okay, come back, guys.
保罗
Paul.
史密斯
Whoa. Smith.
保罗
Paul.
他的尸体怎么搞的？
The hell's going onwith his body?
难道压力液化…
Did the pressure...liquefy...
保罗，别动！天啊
Paul, holdstill! God!
这是什么东西？
What is that thing?
我只知道它在吃尸体…然后突然攻击我
All I know is that it waseating a dead body and then it came at me.
你干嘛？
Em, what are you doing?
我在找它的…
Uh, I'm just looking for its...
不要…
Oh, no, no!
看吧，找它的嘴巴
Looking for its mouth.
它还活着吗？
Is it still alive?
没有 -我会杀了它
- No, no, no. - 'Cause I will kill it.
我好像碰到一条神经
I think I just touched a nerve.
诺拉，还有多远？
Norah, how muchfurther do we have?
离海底200公尺
Two hundred metersaway from the bottom.
它没有眼睛
It doesn't have any eyes.
它们怎么受到光吸引？
How are they attractedto the light?
天啊，你们看
Oh, my God, look at this.
也许它们就像蛾
Maybe they're like moths.
水底蛾
Underwater moths.
这就像爪子
It's like talons.
这可能是新的物种
I think this might bea new species.
我们能帮它命名吗？
Do we get to name it?
是我射杀它的，我来命名
I shot it. I'm naming it.
我没在深海看过这种海底生物
I've never seensea life like this down here.
除非我们钻进了一个热水坑
Unless... Unless we boredinto a hydrothermal pocket.
如果持续的热能能够维持生命…
If it was sustained heatthat could support life...
搞屁啊？
Are you serious?
大家冷静，冷静
Everybody stay calm. Stay calm.
我的天啊
- Oh, my God. - Norah, what'd you get?
诺拉，发现什么？
没有，不只是灯，整个系统都挂了
Nothing.It's not just the lights.
你能打空档吗？再来用滑行的
Can you put us in neutral?Glide the rest of the way?
好
Yeah.
我们能接近缆索吗？
We have access to the cable?
如果能脱离，没问题
If we can disengage, definitely.
什么声音？
What was that?
最好不要是什么电影深海怪兽
This better not be some Twenty Thousand LeaguesUnder the Sea shit, man.
保罗 -搞什么鬼？
- Paul. - What the hell? I'm just joking.
我开玩笑的，但听来外面有东西
I'm just joking. But it does sound like there's something out there.
现在问这有点怪，那是婴儿吗？
It's probably not a good timeto ask, but is that a baby?
该关上那道门吗？
Should we close that door?
我去关，我去关门
I'm gonna close it.I'm gonna close that door.
好
Okay.
我们得想办法下去
We gotta find a way to get down.
我们完全脱离了，怎么没动静
We're completely disengaged.I don't know why we're not moving yet.
靠！ -天啊
Oh, my God!
那是什么东西？
What the hell was that?
天啊 -开普勒爆炸了
- Oh, my God! - The Kepler exploded!
开普勒
The Kepler!
惨了…
Oh, shit, shit, shit!
开普勒
我们快走，队长！
Captain!
进入压力舱
Into the pressure chamber!
抵达海床前必须打开外舱口
We have to openthe outside hatch before we hit the seafloor!
不然会撞毁，快！
Or we get crushed! Move!
进水…
Flood it! Flood it!
戴头盔，灯给我
Helmet, now!Here we go! Come on!
救命啊
Help!
等一下
Hang on!
快，打开舱口
Here we go.Open the hatch!
好了
All right.
快跑…
Run! Run! Run!
小心…
Watch it! Watch it!
诺拉
Norah.
大伙，我在这里
Hey, guys!I'm over here.
到绿灯这边，我在入口
Come to the green light.I'm at the entrance.
小心，史密斯
Watch out, Smith!
爱蜜莉，小心
Emily, watchout!
眼睛闭上
Keep your eyes closed.
别睁开
Keep 'em closed.
我不知道怎么回事
I don't knowwhat happened.
快带他走
Come on, take him.
到油管入口
To the pipeline entrance!
快点
Come on.
门打不开
I can't getthe goddamn door open!
史密斯，听到了吗？
Smith, can you hear me?
不会有事，兄弟，你不会有事
It's gonna be okay, buddy.You're gonna be okay.
（中途站，失压）
（加压）
快
Come on.
别让他挡住门
Let's get him clearof the door!
让他起来…
Get him up. Get him up.
Get him up.Get him up. Get him up.
怎么了？没事吧？
What happened? Are you okay?
他吸入一点烟，没事
He inhaled some fumes.He's okay.
他的氧气过滤器撞到
His oxygen scrubber took a hit.
大家都看到了吧？外面有东西
We all saw this, right?There are things out there.
我们完蛋了
Fuck our lives!
看吧？外面有东西
See?There's something out there.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
保罗，别讲了，只是残骸掉下来
Paul, stop.It's just debris falling.
诺拉，启动载具
Norah, call the mover.
好
All right.
看着我
Look at me.
你还看得到吗？
How's your sight?
很好
I'm good.
不会有事的
- It's gonna be all right, man. - Okay.
我没密码，打不开
I don't have the code.I-I can't get in here.
捂住耳朵
Ears.
算了
Eh, forget it.
帮我一下
- Give me your hand. - Two, three!
二，三
不会有事的
It's gonna be fine, buddy. Yeah.
好，我们搭这台到中点站
All right. We ride thisto the Midpoint Station.
（深钻通道，深度10.3公里）
我们到半途了
We're halfway there, guys.
就快到了
Halfway there.
保罗，停车，它不能在深水中前进
Paul, stop the cart.
停下来
Stop it.
好多水
That's a lot of water.
帮浦大概塞住了
The pumps are probably jammed.
要是不能恢复正常呢？
What happensif they don't turn back on?
有人要回答吗？
Anybody else wanna take that?
没有？
No?
在书里，爱丽丝大哭，差点溺死在自己的泪水中
In the book, Alice cried so much
幸好她能游泳
Luckily, she could swim.
后来情况变得很艰困
It got pretty roughfor her after that.
绝对有东西跟着我们
There's definitelysomething following us.
我真的快要剉屎了
Okay. I'm getting very closeto shitting myself.
看来有人收到食物包裹喔
Looks like somebody gota care package.
玉米棒和…
Cheetos and...
真讽刺
Oh, the irony.
我好爱棉花糖派
I love MoonPies.
这是某个人的东西
This is someone's stuff.
这全是某个人的…
This is all someone's...
天啊
Oh, my God.
继续走…
Keep moving. Keep moving.
好
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
加油，快到了。应该在前方300公尺
Come on, guys,we're almost there. It should be 300 meters ahead.
是这里吗？
Is this it?
我们不能回头
We can't go back.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
太狭小了
It's too tight.
糟糕
Oh, no.
我们得找另一条路
We've got to findanother way.
我最娇小，我去看看
I'm the smallest. Let me check.
拿着
Here.
好
Okay.
帮你扣上安全索
Let me connect you with my line.
扣好了
Attached.
谢谢
Thank you.
我过来了，这里空间很大
All right, I'm through.It's open out here.
你们绝对过得来，会很挤…
It's really tight but...
好
- Okay. - Huh?
我们派爱蜜莉过去
We're sending Emily.
好
Yeah, okay.
扣好了
Attached.
队长出发了
Captain'son his way.
过来
Hey, come here.
很好
Nice.
嘿，你还撑得住吗？
How you holding up?
我可以。我本来要吃这个
I'm okay.
小保罗和我认为你应该拿给你女友
that you shouldgive it to your girl.
棉花糖派 -对啊
- MoonPie. - Yeah.
棉花糖派
MoonPie.
谢了
Thanks, man.
她很棒
She's pretty cool.
千万别搞砸了
Gotta make surenot to screw that up.
嗯
Yeah.
史密斯
Smith.
换你，加油
Your turn. Come on.
队长过去了
All right, Cap's through.I'm going.
我出发了。大伙，我要过来了
All right, guys.I'm coming through.
你在里面还好吗？
How are you doing in there, buddy?
想要兔宝宝暖炉吗？
You want your bunny heater?
不管了，我们过去
All right, forget this.We're going in.
你还好吗？ -还好
Hey. You okay?
保罗，你听得见吗？
- Paul, can you hear me? - Yeah.
没事吧？ -没事
- You okay? - Yeah.
那是什么？
- What is that? - Huh?
保罗，听到了吗？
Paul?Paul, are you reading?
别闹了，快过来
Don't screw around. Let's go.
保罗，收到了吗？
Hey, Paul, you copy?
我们要拉你过来
We're gonna pull you through.
好，拉 -好
- All right, pull. - All right.
开始
Here we go.
加油 -我在拉…
- Come on. - I'm pulling. I'm pulling.
快
Come on.
可恶
Shit!
再拉，加油
Come on, come on.
他来了
There he is.
你吓死我了
You scared the shit out of me.
后面有东西，像妖瘦男那种
There's something back there.Some Slender Man-type shit.
不好笑
Hey, that's not funny.
我的安全索怎么了？
What's wrong with my line?
史密斯，解开，他被缠住了
Smith, unclip.He's all tangled up.
好了，抓住他了 -不
- Okay, I got it. - Oh, no!
解开…我在弄…
Unclip, unclip, unclip!
小保罗拿去
Take Lil Paul! Take Lil Paul!
头盔给我
Give me my helmet!
它在水底拉我
It's pulling me underwater!
他被拉走了，头盔
He's going! Helmet!
帮我戴头盔 -头盔，快戴上。抓住他 -我在抓
- My helmet! - Helmet, now! Get it on! Get it on!
抓住他… -我抓不住了
Grab him! Grab him!
抓住他… -我抓到了
我抓不住他
I can't hold him!
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
保罗
Paul!
快离开
Get out of the water!
爱蜜莉快走 -到隔舱壁去
- Emily, go! - Get to the bulkhead!
（中途站，海神级钻凿点）
（深度10.4公里）
呼叫友台…我是卢西安队长
Calling CQ. Calling CQ.This is Captain Lucien.
我们在中途站，这里严重受损
We're at the Midway Station.It's heavily damaged.
不晓得它还能撑多久
Not sure how long it will last.
有人听到吗？
Does anyone copy?
它把他扯出深潜装
It ripped him out of the suit.
它竟把他从深潜装里扯出去
It ripped him right outof his goddamn suit.
什么鬼东西能那样？
What could do that?
立即开始撤离至海面
Begin evacuation to surface immediately.
呼叫，听到了吗？
CQ, do you copy?
看守塔上线了
Overwatchtower is online.
发生什么事？
What is happening?
那个钻头重达六千吨
That drill weighs 6,000 tons.
怎么会被扯成那样？
How did it getripped up like that?
是我们造成的
We did this.
我们钻凿海底
We drilledthe bottom of the ocean.
我们夺取太多了
We took too much.
现在海洋在报复
And now she's taking back.
我们不该到这里来的
We're not supposed to bedown here.
谁都不该
No one is.
她说得没错
She's not wrong.
听好
Listen.
我知道保罗走了
I know Paul's gone, but...
但我们不能待在这里
we can't stay here.
史密斯的深潜装呢？
What about Smith's suit?
我看看你的氧气过滤器
Let me take a lookat your oxygen scrubber.
来吧
- Hmm. - Come on.
怎么样？
How is it?
这套深潜装撑不住的
The suit's not gonna make it.
你们自己去吧
You guys gottago without me. We... I'm...
我只会拖累大家
I'm just gonna bedead weight out there.
我不能再失去任何人 -我也是
- I can't lose anybody else. - Me neither.
别说了
Stop.
史密斯，你能靠我
Okay,Smith, you can lean on me.
呼吸短而浅
Take short,shallow breaths.
好
Okay.
不会有事的，我罩你
It's gonna be all right.I got you.
看到21号标记
Okay, there's Marker 21.
我们跟着标记走就行了
All we do now is followthese across the plateau.
罗巴克站就在0号标记旁
The Roebuck Stationwill be at Marker Zero.
你看到什么？
What did you see? Huh?
不知道
I don't know.
我刚看到了 -天啊
- I just saw it. - Oh, my God!
我看到了
I saw that.
把他放下来
Set him down.
那是什么？
What was that?
那到底是什么？
What the hell was that?
在哪里？…
Where is it? Where is it?
关灯
Turn off the lights.
不要动
Don't move.
我打开我的红外线
I'm gonna turn my IR on.
诺拉，有收到我的画面吗？
Norah, did youget my feed?
有
Yeah.
史密斯？
Smith?
史密斯呢？诺拉？
Where's Smith? Norah?
他在哪？ -有看到他吗？
- Where is he? - Do you see him?
他去哪了？
Where'd he go?
史密斯 -爱蜜莉
- Smith! - Emily.
史密斯？ -史密斯
- Smith? - Smith!
爱蜜莉，救命
Emily. Help.
那是他的脚 -我过去
- That's his foot. - I'm going.
我钩住你
I'm hookingonto you. Here.
看到他了，我抓住他了
I see him.
他还活着…
He's alive. He's alive.
我拖他回来
I'm pulling him back.
好
Okay.
推他过来，我们抓他的脚
Just push him.We'll grab his feet.
史密斯，听到了吗？
Smith, can you hear us?
史密斯，拜托，你听到了吗？
Smith, please! Can you hear us?
我去拿枪
I gotta grab the gun.
什么？别管枪了
What?Forget the gun.
队长，别拿
Captain, leave it.
队长
Cap.
队长，你在干嘛？
Cap, what are you doing?
诺拉… -不！
No!
不！
诺拉？
Norah?
你还好吗？
You okay?
我看不到你，你看得到我吗？
I can't see you.Can you see me?
诺拉？
Norah?
你在哪里？
Where are you?
在你下方，有看见我吗？
I'm underneath you.Can you see me?
队长，听见了吗？
Cap, canyou hear me?
诺拉
Norah.
你在哪？
Where are you?
我在这里，下面
I'm here.Underneath.
我被缠住了，有看见我吗？
I'm all tangled.Can you see me?
有
Yeah.
好，等一下
Okay, hold on.
它在哪里？
Where is it?
不知道
I don't know.
带我离开
Get meout of here.
好 -可恶
- Okay. - Shit.
我看怎么帮你，等等
Okay, let me seeif I can help you. Hold on.
你能拿到我的刀子吗？
Can you reach my knife?
那是什么？
What was that?
诺拉
Norah.
它回来了吗？
Is it back?
你看到什么？
What do you see?
它回来了吗？
Is it back?
诺拉
Norah!
我抓住你了…我在你旁边
Oh, I got you. I got you.I'm with you.
我在
I'm with you.
压力程度危险
Pressure level critical.
我们上升太快，压力会害死我们
We'rerising too fast! The pressure's gonnakill us both!
请减缓上升速度
Please slow ascent.
诺拉
Norah.
放开
Let go.
深潜装完整性10%
Suitintegrity, ten percent.
诺拉，看着我
Norah,look at me.
放手，该死！
Let go, God damn it!
我不能放…
No, I can't. I can't. I can't.
4%
Four percent.
3%
Three percent.
不…
No, no, no. No, no, no.
2%
Two percent.
没关系
It's gonna be all right.
不，不要！
No, don't do that.
1%
One percent.
不要…
Don't do that!Don't do that!
爱蜜莉，听见了吗？
Emily, canyou hear me?
（薛波）
（薛波钻井，废弃探勘站）
（深度10.8公里）
爱蜜莉，史密斯，听到了吗？
Emily, Smith,can you hear me?
我还活着，我在旧的薛波钻井站
I'm still alive. I'm atthe old Shepard drill.
（通力合作行得通）
There's no...
这里没有逃生舱，但我能呼吸，还有空气
There's no pods herebut I can breathe. I have some air.
如果你们在外面…
If you guys areout there...
（单打独斗违反公司政策）
有人听到了吗？
Is anyone reading?
爱蜜莉，你听见了吗？
Emily, can you hear me?
你们听到了吗？
Can you guys hear me?
队长
Cap.
（卢西安）
（怀念艾丽卢西安，14岁）
艾丽
Allie.
对不起
I'm sorry.
（罗巴克油井预定地）
我会继续说话，不知道你们能否听见
Guys, I'm just gonnakeep talking.
我会沿着东南线走
I'm followingthe southeast line.
跟着标记
Following the markers.
到罗巴克
To the Roebuck.
我以前好爱海洋
I used to love the ocean.
它就像一个超大培养皿
It was like a giantpetri dish, you know?
爱蜜莉，是你吗？
Em, is that you?
我知道你…
I know that you have...
一周每天有不同的夏威夷衬衫可穿
a different Hawaiian shirtfor every day of the week.
爱蜜莉，我听见你了，是你吗？
Emily, I can hear you.Is that you?
即使我不了解培养皿以外的你
Even thoughI don't know you outside of thispetri dish...
爱蜜莉
Emily.
但我知道你会听我说话
But I knowthat you listen to me.
逗我笑
And you make me laugh.
我爱你
I love you.
你知道吗？
You know?
爱蜜莉？
Em?
Emily?
我要你知道
I needed you to know.
爱蜜莉？
Emily?
嘿
Hey.
爱蜜莉，我就在你后面
Emily, I'm rightbehind you.
你听得见吗？
Hey, can you hear me?
爱蜜莉
Hey, Emily.
爱蜜莉 -不，拜托！
- Emily! - No! Please!
拜托别过来
Please stay back!
爱蜜莉，停！
Emily, stop!
爱蜜莉…
Emily. Hey, hey.
爱蜜莉，睁开眼睛
Hey. Em? Em? Em?Open your eyes.
睁开眼睛，是我
Emily, open your eyes.It's me.
我抓着你
Hey, I got you.
我抓着你 -诺拉，我以为你…
- I got you. - Norah, I thought you...
你没事 -诺拉
- You're okay. - Norah...
诺拉，我以为你死了
Norah, I thought you...I thought you were dead.
史密斯呢？他没事吧？
How's Smith? Is he okay?
对
Yes, yes.
他在这里，他还活着
He's here. He's alive.
好，这最重要
Okay. That's whatmatters, right?
对
Yes.
起来，过来
Come on, let's get up.Come here.
我没有走很远
I didn't get very far.
开什么玩笑？
Are you kidding me?
我好为你骄傲
I am so proud of you.
我根本不敢相信，真的
I-I can't evenbelieve it, honestly.
你的氧气一定…
Your air must be...
我看看你的氧气，你一定…
Let me check your air,though. You must be so...
不，我…
No, I'm just...
我想…
I figured...
我要继续走
I'm just gonna walk.
好，好主意
Okay. That's a good plan.
队长呢？
The captain?
去带史密斯过来，好吗？
Just grab Smith. Okay?
别多想，走吧
Don't think aboutit. Come on.
天啊，我觉得超嗨的 -嗨翻了
God, I feel high. Freebie.
氧气不足造成的
It's the lowoxygen thing.
我手指没感觉了
I can'tfeel my fingers.
你的狗叫什么名字？
What's your dog's name?
甜妮，你的呢？
Tenny. Yours?
好可爱，小詹
That's cute. Jim.
小詹？
Jim?
它惹麻烦时就会叫詹姆斯
James if he getsin trouble.
其实它是我未婚夫的狗
He was my fiance's dog,actually.
你们分手了？
You guys split up?
没有
No.
当然没有
No way. He, um...
他是史密斯的死党
He was Smith'sbest friend, actually.
以前我们常一起潜水
We used to alldive together.
有天他想潜水，我很累，让他自己去
He wanted to goout one night. I was tired.I let him go alone, and...
结果他一去不回，我觉得不对劲
he just took forever. I knew somethingwas wrong. So I...
通知搜救队去找他
I called Search and Rescueand went down to look for him.
怎么找都找不到
I just... couldn'tfind him.
抱歉，你不必听这些
I'm sorry. You don'tneed to hear that right now.
很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
只是那种…无法改变现实的无力感
It's just that feeling ofbeing powerless to change anything.
让我痛不欲生
It almost killed me.
我逼史密斯发誓绝不在水底谈这个
I made Smith swear to me he would never talkabout it down here.
你真的很爱他吧？
You really love him, huh?
嗯
Yeah.
好棒
That's really cool.
继续拖就是了
You just gottakeep pulling.
那是什么？
What is that?
那是什么光？
What is that glow?
是钻井站
It's the drill.
是罗巴克站
It's the Roebuck.
天啊，我们到了
Oh, my God.Oh, my God, we made it.
（罗巴克站，崔莱顿级钻凿点）
（深度11.1公里）
加油…
Come on. Come on.
我们快到了
We're almost there.
快到了，到绿灯那边
Almost there.Just to the green light.
它们是什么？
What are they?
关灯
Turn yourlights off.
Turn your lights off.
天啊
Oh, my God.
它们从哪冒出来的？
Where are they all coming from?
门就在那边
The door is right there.
那边
Right there.
它们像在睡觉，或冬眠
They look likethey're sleeping.
先想办法进去再说
Let's just focuson getting inside.
警告，氧气量严重不足
Warning.Oxygen levels critical.
哔，哔
Beep, beep.
八成不是好事
That's probably not good.
继续走，爱蜜莉，继续走
Keep going. Emily,keep going.
拖史密斯到门口
Get Smith to the door.
爱蜜莉，快带他过去
Emily, take him. Go.
爱蜜莉，去啊
Emily, go.
走！
Go!
爱蜜莉，快走
Emily, go!
靠！
Fuck!
什么…
What the...
惨了
Oh, shit!
诺拉
Norah!
警告，氧气量严重不足
Warning.Oxygen levels critical.
氧气量严重不足
Oxygen levels critical.
警告，氧气量严重不足
Warning.Oxygen levels critical.
氧气量严重不足
Oxygen levels critical.
警告，氧气量严重不足
Warning.Oxygen levels critical.
Warning. Oxygen levels critical.
等一下
One sec.
史密斯
Smith.
来
Come on.
史密斯
Smith.
请立即前往最近的逃生舱准备撤离
Please find your wayto the nearest pod deck for immediate evacuation.
我们快去找逃生舱
Come on,we gotta get to the pods.
快点
Come on, bud.
立即开始撤离至海面
Begin evacuationto surface immediately.
我得找到操作指南
I gotta findthe directory.
G层受损
DeckG compromised.
进水已控制
Flooding contained.
靠
Fuck.
快啊…
Come on, come on, come on.
欢迎登上罗巴克站，天恩工业的泰坦级钻井
Welcome aboardthe Roebuck. Tian Industries'titan-class drill.
这里…
Oh, here! Here, here!
每年钻取原油高达1400亿吨
Excavatinga whopping 140 billion tons of crude a year.
罗巴克是天恩工业，生产能源的未来希望
The Roebuck is the future
哇靠 -天恩工业
- Holy shit. - Tian Industries.
你将见到我们的雄心壮志
We've got big thingsin store for you.
欢迎登上罗巴克站，天恩工业的泰坦级钻井
Welcome aboardthe Roebuck. Tian Industries'titan-class drill.
往这边…
All right, come on,this way. This way.
隔舱壁关闭
Bulkheadsclosed.
进水已控制
Flooding contained.
不…
Oh, no! No, no, no!
指挥舰桥受损
Commandbridge compromised.
这边 进水已控制
- This way! Come on! - Flooding contained.
欢迎登上罗巴克站，天恩工业的泰坦级钻井
Welcomeaboard the Roebuck. Tian Industries'titan-class drill.
快…
Go, go, go!
F层受损
DeckF compromised.
隔舱壁关闭
Bulkheads closed.
进水已控制
Flooding contained.
快点
Come on.
请立即前往最近的逃生舱准备撤离
Please find your wayto the nearest pod deck for immediate evacuation.
太好了
Yes! Yes!
立即开始撤离至海面
Begin evacuation to surface immediately.
太好了
Yes! Yes!
（无法操作）
Warning. Warning.Pod non-operational.
（故障）
警告…逃生舱无法操作
Warning. Warning.Pod non-operational.
好了吗，诺拉？
Are we set, Norah?
逃生舱无法操作
Pod non-operational.
好了
Yeah.
准备好了
Yeah, we're good.
逃生舱够吗？ -够
- Do we have enough pods? - Yep.
确定？有几艘？ -三艘
Are you sure?How many do we have?
三艘？ -对
We got three,we got three.
好，你先走 -我们紧跟在后
- Three? - Yep.
你们快走 -不行
- Okay, you go, you go. You guys go. - No way.
你们先走，我最后
No, you go first. I'll go last.
我最后 -别这样
- I'll go last. - Hey. Come on.
小心头
Hey. Watch your head.
F层受损
Deck Fcompromised.
你必须撑下去，好吗？
You have to make it, okay?
你保证？
You promise me?
我保证
I promise.
进水已控制
Floodingcontained.
谢谢你在海底拖着我走
Hey, thanks for dragging meacross the bottom of the ocean.
不客气
Any time.
可是千万别再来一次
Except never,never again, please.
没问题
Fair enough.
逃生舱出航程序启动
Pod launchsequence activated.
待会见，好了
I'll see you soon. Okay.
你带这个走
Here. You gotta take this.
交给保罗的父母
Give it to his folksor something.
靠，小保罗
Shit. Lil Paul.
告诉他们他是我最爱的讨厌鬼
Let 'em know he was my favoritepain in the ass, okay?
会的 -掰
- Will do. - Bye, bud.
立即开始撤离至海面
Begin evacuationto surface immediately.
换你了
Come on, you're up.
不，我殿后，没关系，你先走
No, I can take the last one.It's fine, it's fine. Seriously, you go.
不行，快上去
No. Come on, get in.
不，真的
No, seriously.
你根本不会操作，走吧
You can't even operatethis thing. Let's go.
它有什么问题？
What's wrong with it?
上去
Get in the pod.
爱蜜莉，我能修理，没空争执了
Emily, I can fix it.We don't have time for this.
天啊，我不要丢下你 -快点
- Oh, my God, no. I'm not leaving you. - Come on.
你不能丢下他
No. You're not leaving him.
B层受损
Deck B compromised.
留下来你会没命。那我们所为何来？
If you stay here,you're gonna die here. And then what are we even doing?
我留下来陪你，我们一起修
I will stay with you and wecan fix it together, okay?
没空吵这个，快进去
We don't have time for that.Come on, get in the pod.
你…诺拉
Hey! What are you... Norah.
知道我想多做什么一秒钟吗？
Do you know what I would dofor one more second?
跟山姆多相处一秒钟
Just one more second with Sam?
什么事都好
Anything. Anything.
走吧，你还有一辈子
Go. You have a whole life.
诺拉，住手 -爱蜜莉
- No, no. Norah, stop it. - Emily. Emily.
住手
Stop it!
对不起
Sorry. Sorry.
好了
There we go.
逃生舱出航程序启动
Pod launchsequence activated.
你最好平安上去，好吗？
You better make itup there, okay?
不会有事的
It's gonna be all right.
好吗？
Okay?
B层受损
Deck B compromised.
隔舱壁关闭
Bulkheads closed.
请立即前往最近的逃生舱准备撤离
Please find your wayto the nearest pod deck for immediate evacuation.
立即开始撤离至海面
Begin evacuationto surface immediately.
A层受损
Deck A compromised.
隔舱壁关闭，进水已控制
Bulkheads closed.Flooding contained.
请立即前往最近的逃生舱准备撤离
Please find your wayto the nearest pod deck for immediate evacuation.
立即开始撤离至海面
Begin evacuationto surface immediately.
发现压力异常
Pressure anomaliesdetected.
有些事将让你感到无力
There are thingsthat will happen
让你觉得渺小，但仅止于此
and make you feelinsignificant.
它们只是感觉
They're just feelings.
立即开始撤离至海面
Begin evacuationto surface immediately.
有时候你必须停止感受
And sometimesyou have to stop feeling.
开始行动
Start doing.
外来物体接近逃生舱
Foreign objectsapproaching pods.
距离60公尺
NDistance to contact, 60 meters.
进入核心终端
Accessing core terminal.
知道我们底下有什么吗？
You knowwhat we're sitting on?
大量的能量，无处可去
A lot of energy. With nowhere to go.
（核心爆炸模拟）
核心熔毁开始
Coremeltdown in progress.
一分钟后熔毁
One minute untilmeltdown.
我们有60秒
You got 60 seconds.
在黑暗中会失去时间感
You lose your sense of timein the dark.
四，三，二，一
Four, three, two, one.
把这鬼东西炸烂吧
So let'slight this shit up.
（钻井意外有两人获救）
（该公司不准员工受访）
（深海灾变 公司拒绝政府协助搜救）
（天恩工业拒绝透露太平洋油井崩塌细节）
（意外前出现可疑异常）
（机密）
（罗巴克油井灾变）
（两名生还者的访谈列为机密）
（监视器影片损毁）
（清理与重建尽快展开）
（天恩工业将恢复钻油）
（先前意外的细节依然不明）
翻译：亚伦